Finding Aid for Eric Stein Papers 1955-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Eric Stein Papers
1955-2002
Stein, Eric (1913- )
Professor at the University of Michigan Law School. Specialized in International Law, having served in the U.S. Department of State. Stein was born in the Czech and Slovak Federal Republic in 1913. The bulk of the Eric Stein collection relates to his research and writings, and his career as a law professor at the University of Michigan. The papers, dated from 1955 through 1996, have been arranged topically into six series: Biographical, Ford Foundation, Correspondence, Courses, Topical Files and Writings.
861074 Aa 2
22.7 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection ( 7031 ) was donated in three accessions, by Eric Stein in February 1984, April 2007, and by the University of Michigan Law School in 1999.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open for research.
Eric Stein was born in Holice, in the Czech and Slovak Federal Republic, on July 8, 1913, the son of Zikmund Stein and Herminia Zalud Stein. He received his J.U.D. from Charles University, Prague, in 1937, and his J.D. from the University of Michigan in 1942. Following service with the U.S. Army Allied Commission for Italy, Legal Subcommission from 1942 to 1946, Stein maintained a high profile in international affairs. He served with the U.S. Department of State from 1946 to 1955 and held additional positions with the U.S. United Nations delegation.
In 1955, Stein married Virginia Elizabeth Rhine. In the same year, he began a long and distinguished tenure on the University of Michigan Law School faculty. After two years as associate professor, Stein was promoted to full professor in 1957. Stein's professional and legal interests kept him actively involved in international studies. He was co-director, with William W. Bishop, Jr., of International and Comparative Legal Studies from 1958 to 1976, and director from 1976 to 1981. In this capacity he promoted multi-national studies and programs, such as an exchange program for faculty and students between the University of Michigan and the Free University of Brussels, Belgium. Stein was an active participant on several university committees, and these memberships also reflect his international orientation. During his tenure, he served on the Faculty Advisory Committee on International Programs (FACIP), on the Vandenberg Lecture Committee, and with the Center for Western European Studies. His achievements have been recognized by two honorary doctorates (from the Université Libre Brussels, Belgium, 1978, and from the West-Bohemian University Pilsen, Czech Republic, 1997). He also worked to coordinate the Ford Foundation grants for International and Comparative Legal Studies at the Law School, and for over a decade wrote the Law School's submission to the university's general Ford Foundation annual reports.
Much of Stein's scholarship has focused on transnational economic institutions, and on other international aspects of the law such as disarmament and weapons control. His was among the first courses in the world on the European Common Market, and students came from across Europe to the United States to take it. His published books include: American Enterprise in the European Common Market: A Legal Profile, editor (1960); Courts and Free Markets: Perspectives from the United States and Europe (1982), Czecho/Slovakia: Ethnic Conflict/Constitutional Fissures/Negotiated Breakup (1997), Diplomats, Scientists and Politicians: The United States and the Nuclear Test Ban Negotiations (1966) and Thoughts from a Bridge: A Retrospective of Writings on New Europe and American Federalism (2000).
Stein retired from the Law School in 1983, and after being reappointed several times to teach courses, he retired for the last time in 1990, though he continues to guest lecture as professor emeritus. Stein was also invited as an advisor to the Czech and Slovak governments on issues of constitutional drafting in 1990-1993. In 2001, President Vaclav Havel awarded him the Medal of Merit First Degree for Outstanding Scholarly Achievement of the Czech Republic, and was made an honorary Czech citizen of Holice.
The bulk of the Eric Stein collection relates to his research and writings, and his career as a law professor at the University of Michigan. The papers were received in two main installments, 1999 and 2007. As such, the papers are arranged and described as two separate accessions. The second installment of papers received in 2007 extends the earlier series and adds one new series pertaining to the Czech Constitution.
Subjects:
Ford Foundation.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan--Grants.; University of Michigan--Law School.; International law.; Disarmament.; Constitutional law--Michigan.; Constitutional law--Czechoslovakia.; Constitutional law--Czech Republic.; Constitutional law--Slovakia.
- Biographical
  The Biographical series (0.2 linear feet) contains biographical documents, but little of a personal nature. The majority of documents in this series are university personnel forms which Stein filled out yearly between 1958 and 1976. A few forms are missing from the series. Though the information contained in the forms is somewhat repetitive, they do provide a brief yearly synopsis of the classes Stein taught, his professional activities, and his publications. The most interesting materials in this series relate to Stein's successful application for a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1962-1963.
  - Biography, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Faculty Reports (Cook, etc.), 1965-1986 (Box 1)
  - General (Box 1)
  - Guggenheim Application, 1961 (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan Faculty Personnel Record (Form A), 1958-1976 (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan Faculty Personnel Record (Form B), 1958-1976 (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan Faculty Report on Publications, Research and Activities, 1964-1970 (Box 1)
- Ford Foundation, 1963-1973
  The series Ford Foundation (0.5 linear feet, 1963-1973) documents Stein's involvement with the Ford Foundation grants to the Law School from the late 1950s to the early 1970s. For a period of ten years between 1963 and 1973, Stein compiled the annual report from the Law School to the Ford Foundation. He was also involved in budgeting grant money for professors and students who were working on projects concerned with international and comparative law. Much of the documentation for these complementary activities consists of memos and correspondence between Stein, various deans, and the rest of the law faculty. Some background materials for the university's grant proposals are included.
  - Ford Report 1964 "International and Comparative Legal Studies at Michigan, 1954-1964 a decade of change" (Box 1)
  - Ford Proposal, 1966
    - Background material (Box 1)
    - Faculty requests, A-G (Box 1)
    - Faculty requests, H-Z (Box 1)
  - Ford Grant, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Ford Budgets
    - July 1, 1965-June 30, 1966 (Box 1)
    - July 1, 1966-June 30, 1967 (Box 1)
      (#37444)
    - July 1, 1966-June 30, 1967 (Box 1)
      (#37413)
    - July 1, 1967-June 30, 1968 (Box 1)
    - July 1, 1968-June 30, 1969 (Box 1)
    - July 1, 1969-June 30, 1970 (Box 1)
    - July 1, 1970-June 30, 1971 (Box 1)
    - July 1, 1971-June 30, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Material for Ford Report
    - 1963-1964 (Box 1)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 1)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 1)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 1)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 1)
      (faculty statements)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series is organized into two subseries, 1955-1992 and 1973-2001, reflecting the two major accessions of Stein material. Each of the subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent/subject and is an integration of numerous small alphabetical runs that Stein had maintained. There is some overlap in corespondents and subject matter between the two subseries.
  - 1955-1992
    The Correspondence series (14.2 linear feet, 1955-1996) covers the years that Stein was involved with the University of Michigan, from 1955 to 1996, but the materials are not restricted to his University activities. The relationships with individuals and organizations, which he cultivated at the State Department, are represented here, as well as his Law School research and teaching, his travels and visiting professorships in Europe, and some personal matters. Correspondence with other professors with whom he worked closely on international law, such as William Warner Bishop, Jr., and Hessel Yntema, can be found here. Additional correspondence appears in the 2007 accession.
    This subseries is a compilation of several different runs of alphabetical correspondence, each covering a different time period. As these time periods were somewhat blurred, the correspondence has been organized into one alphabetical series. It includes such general headings as "A, 1956-1994," as well as headings for individuals. However, letters from an individual who is listed in a separate folder may also be found under the general heading. Both incoming and outgoing correspondence can be found.
    - A
      - 1956-1994, 4 folders (Box 1)
      - Societies and Associations, 1957-1961 (Box 1)
    - American Bar Association
      - 1962-1981, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - European Law Committee, 1983 (Box 1)
      - International Law Section, 1984 (Box 1)
    - American Journal of Comparative Law, 1963-1976 (Box 1)
    - American Journal of International Law, 1962-1995; 4 folders (Box 1)
    - American Society of International Law
      - 1967-1995, 4 folders (Box 1)
      - Bellagio Meeting, 1966-1970 (Box 1)
      - Board of Review and Development, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
      - Panel on International Trade Policy and Institutions, 1974 (Box 2)
      - Panel on Regional Integration, 1967-1972 (Box 2)
    - American University Lecture, 1967-1974 (Box 2)
    - Anderson, Norman (University of London Institute of Advanced Legal Studies), 1975-1976 (Box 2)
    - Angelo, Homer G. (University of California, Davis), 1974-1985 (Box 2)
    - Anti-Dumping and Anti-Subsidy, 1987; undated (Box 2)
    - Association of American Law Schools, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
    - The Atlantic Institute, 1964-1970 (Box 2)
    - Atomic Energy Project, 1958-1959 (Box 2)
    - B, 1955-1995; 13 folders (Box 2)
    - Ball, George W., 1961-1968 (Box 3)
    - Bancroft, Harding F. (New York Times), 1960-1968 (Box 3)
    - Barav, Ami (1977-1988) (Box 3)
    - Baxter, Richard (Harvard University), 1972-1980 (Box 3)
    - Bebr, Gerhard, 1972-1984; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Bechhoefer, Bernhard G., 1963-1971 (Box 3)
    - Bellagio Conference
      - 1977-1979 (Box 3)
      - Circular Letters, 1978-1980 (Box 3)
      - "Proposal for a Joint European-American Study on the Role of the Judiciary in Economic and Political Integration,", 1976-1977 (Box 3)
    - Bendix Corporation (Michael W. Blumenthal), 1962-1976 (Box 3)
    - Berlin (Wissenschaftskolleg zu Berlin/Institute for Advanced Study Berlin), 1983-1991; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Bilder, Richard B., 1960-1974 (Box 3)
    - Bishop, William Jr., 1971-1988 (Box 3)
    - Blasi, Vincent, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Publishers, 1969-1982; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Brinkhorst, Laurens J., 1970-1973 (Box 3)
    - British Institute of International and Comparative Law, 1961-1964 (Box 3)
    - Brugge (College d'Europe/College of Europe), 1987-1988 (Box 3)
    - Brussels (University of Brussels), 1982-1986 (Box 3)
    - Buxbaum, Richard (University of California, Berkeley), 1964-1990; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - C, 1955-1996; 9 folders (Box 3)
    - Cantizares, F. de Solà, 1960-1964 (Box 3)
    - Capotorti, Francesco, 1978-1986 (Box 3)
    - Cappelletti, Mauro, 1979-1983 (Box 3)
    - Carreau, Dominique, 1975-1981 (Box 3)
    - Castenada, Ricardo, 1980-1988 (Box 3)
    - Chicago-Kent College of Law, 1992 (Box 4)
    - Cleveland, Harlan, 1962-1980; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Committee on Legal Education Exchange with China, 1984-1991; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Common Market Law Review, 1974-1987 (Box 4)
    - Costonis, John J., 1966-1973 (Box 4)
    - Czechoslovakia (and other topics), 1992 (Box 4)
    - D, 1956-1995; 10 folders (Box 4)
    - Daig, Hans-Wolfram, 1961-1964 (Box 4)
    - Dainow, Joseph, 1963-1972 (Box 4)
    - Dam, Kenneth W., 1962-1976 (Box 4)
    - D'Amato, Anthony, 1966-1968 (Box 4)
    - Dawson, John P. (Harvard Law School), 1960-1966 (Box 4)
    - De Pauw, Marc, 1978-1991 (Box 4)
    - De Schutter, Bart, 1978-1983 (Box 4)
    - Deak, Francis (Carnegie Endowment for International Peace), 1961-1971 (Box 4)
    - Department of State
      - American Universities Exchange Program, 1964 (Box 4)
      - Clinical Program in International Law, 1972-1979 (Box 4)
      - General, 1960-1974 (Box 4)
    - DePauw, Frans, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Deringer, Arved, 1962-1974 (Box 4)
    - Doehring, Karl, 1966-1970 (Box 4)
    - Donner, A.M., 1961-1980; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - E, 1956-1995; 6 folders (Box 5)
    - Ebb, Lawrence F., 1960-1967 (Box 5)
    - Edwards, Harry T., 1974 (Box 5)
    - Ehlerman, Claus-Dieter, 1977-1984 (Box 5)
    - Elkin, Alexander, 1959-1971 (Box 5)
    - Erler, Georg, 1961-1968 (Box 5)
    - European Trip--Correspondence with secretary, 1962-1963; 1965; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - European University--Florence Reunion Panel, 1989 (Box 5)
    - European University Institute, 1990-1992 (Box 5)
    - F, 1956-1995; 6 folders (Box 5)
    - Falk, Richard A., 1960-1972 (Box 5)
    - Farley, Philip J., 1956-1970 (Box 5)
    - Fikentscher, Wolfgang, 1966-1970 (Box 5)
    - Finkelstein, Lawrence S., 1957-1968 (Box 5)
    - Fisher, John and Trude, 1956-1966 (Box 5)
    - Fitzmaurice, Sir Gerald, 1956-1960 (Box 5)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 6)
      - 1964-1979, 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Budgeting, 1963-1964 (Box 6)
    - Foreign Relations, Council on, 1972-1980 (Box 6)
    - Foreign Scholars, 1958-1961 (Box 6)
    - Fraley, Frederick W., 1957-1961 (Box 6)
    - Friedmann, Wolfgang, 1958-1967 (Box 6)
    - Frowein, Jochen, 1987-1995 (Box 6)
    - Fulda, Carl H., 1962-1970 (Box 6)
    - G, 1956-1995; 8 folders (Box 6)
    - Galabert, M. Jean-Michel, 1979-1981 (Box 6)
    - Ganshof van der Meersch, Walter J., 1965-1978 (Box 6)
    - Garcia-Amador, F.V., 1964-1970 (Box 6)
    - Gardner, Richard N., 1956-1974 (Box 6)
    - Gaudet, Michel, 1957-1974; 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Geck, Wilhelm Karl, 1962-1968 (Box 6)
    - Goebel, Roger J., 1962-1968 (Box 6)
    - Gold, Joseph, 1959-1969 (Box 6)
    - Goldstein, E. Ernest, 1957-1961 (Box 6)
    - Goormaghtigh, John (Dotation Carnegie Pour la Paix Internationale Centre Européen), 1965-1978 (Box 6)
    - Gorla, Gino, 1958-1965 (Box 6)
    - Green, Andrew Wilson, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
    - Grimes, Warren S., 1966-1971 (Box 6)
    - Gross, Ernest A., 1956-1968 (Box 6)
    - Gross, Leo, 1961-1970 (Box 6)
    - Grossfeld, Bernhard, 1967-1977 (Box 6)
    - Grzybowski, Kazimierz, 1959-1973 (Box 6)
    - H, 1956-1995; 9 folders (Box 7)
    - Haas, Ernst B., 1959-1978 (Box 7)
    - Haase-Dubosc, Arnold, 1956-1974 (Box 7)
    - Haber, William (Dean of College of LS&A), 1959-1966 (Box 7)
    - Haber, Wolf, 1957-1980 (Box 7)
    - Haller, Walter, 1968-1970 (Box 7)
    - Hallstein, Walter, 1963-1967 (Box 7)
    - Hamson, Charles J., 1960-1968 (Box 7)
    - Hart, Philip, 1966-1969 (Box 7)
    - Hartley, Robert W. (Brookings Institution), 1956-1962 (Box 7)
    - Harvey, William Burnett, 1960-1990 (Box 7)
    - Hauser, Gustave M., 1959 (Box 7)
    - Hay, Peter (University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign College of Law), 1959-1986; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Hazard, John N., 1959-1969 (Box 7)
    - Heenen, Jacques, 1963-1976 (Box 7)
    - Heidelberg, 1977-1986 (Box 7)
    - Hellner, Jan (University of Stockholm), 1962-1978 (Box 7)
    - Helman, Gerald B., 1959-1977 (Box 7)
    - Henkin, Louis (Columbia University), 1956-1983; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Hexner, Ervin, 1956-1966 (Box 7)
    - Higgins, Rosalyn (The Royal Institute of International Affairs), 1969 (Box 7)
    - Hilboldt, James S., 1981-1989 (Box 7)
    - Homet, Roland S., 1967-1969 (Box 8)
    - Howard, John B., 1961-1969 (Box 8)
    - Hoxter, Curtis J., 1956-1960 (Box 8)
    - Hoya, Thomas W., 1958-1966 (Box 8)
    - Hoyt, Edwin (University of New Mexico), 1961-1967 (Box 8)
    - Humboldt, Alexander von (Association/Foundation/Stiftung), 1981-1990 (Box 8)
    - Humphry, H.G., 1963-1965 (Box 8)
    - Huntley, James R., 1966-1969 (Box 8)
    - Hyde, James N., 1957-1984; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Hydeman, Lee M., 1958-1962 (Box 8)
    - I, 1960-1996; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Inter-American Institute of International Legal Studies Seminar (San Jose, Costa Rica), 1967 (Box 8)
    - International Academy of Comparative Law, 1973-1988; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - International Congress of Comparative Law, Uppsala, 1966 (Box 8)
    - International Law Association, 1990-1993 (Box 8)
    - J, 1956-1994; 4 folders (Box 8)
    - Jackson, John H., 1961-1968 (Box 8)
    - Jacobs, Francis G. (University of London King's College), 1979-1981 (Box 8)
    - Jacobson, Harold, 1962-1974 (Box 8)
    - Japan Program, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Jaeckel, Hugo, 1956-1972 (Box 8)
    - Jessup, Philip C., 1956-1973 (Box 8)
    - Jeantet, Fernand Charles, 1958-1980 (Box 8)
    - Jillson, Robert L., 1960-1972 (Box 8)
    - Johnson, Joseph E., 1956-1971 (Box 8)
    - Juenger, Friedrich K., 1957-1976 (Box 8)
    - K
      - 1956-1987, 6 folders (Box 8)
      - 1988-1995, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Kahn-Freund, Otto, 1958-1979; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Katzenbach, Nicholas deB., 1959-1970 (Box 9)
    - Kearney, Richard D., 1965-1970 (Box 9)
    - King, Henry T., 1959-1971 (Box 9)
    - Kisch, Isaak, 1959-1960 (Box 9)
    - Knobloch, Edgar, 1965-1969 (Box 9)
    - Kopelmanas, Lazare, 1959-1963 (Box 9)
    - Kopp, Hans W., 1959-1981; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Kouba, Jon H., 1964-1967 (Box 9)
    - Kozolchyk, Boris, 1961-1969 (Box 9)
    - Krawielicki, Robert, 1958-1966 (Box 9)
    - Kronstein, Heinrich, 1960-1967 (Box 9)
    - Kuster, Otto, 1968-1971 (Box 9)
    - L, 1956-1995; 7 folders (Box 9)
    - Laba, Gerald Jay, 1965-1969 (Box 9)
    - Ladas, Stephen, 1958-1971 (Box 9)
    - Lagrange, Maurice, 1966-1971 (Box 9)
    - Lando, Ole, 1962-1969 (Box 9)
    - Lauterpacht, Hersch, 1956-1959 (Box 9)
    - Lauwaars, Richard H., 1978-1983 (Box 9)
    - Lawson, F.H., 1958-1964 (Box 9)
    - Leddy, John M., 1961-1969 (Box 9)
    - Lehner, George A., 1976-1989 (Box 9)
    - Leleux, Paul, 1963-1981; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Leonard, L. Larry, 1958-1964 (Box 9)
    - Letiche, John M., 1966-1971 (Box 9)
    - Levit, William H., 1957-1961 (Box 9)
    - Limpens, Jean, 1958-1979 (Box 9)
    - Linde, Hans A., 1963-1981; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Lindsay, Kenneth, 1959-1962 (Box 9)
    - Lipson, Leslie M., 1966-1969 (Box 9)
    - Lissitzyn, Oliver J., 1959-1976 (Box 9)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1957-1969 (Box 9)
    - Mc, 1957-1972 (Box 10)
    - McCarthy, Paul, 1965-1970 (Box 10)
    - MacChesney, Brunson, 1957-1978 (Box 10)
    - MacEachron, David W., 1956-1975 (Box 10)
    - MacKenzie, Kenneth C., 1961-1968 (Box 10)
    - M, 1956-1995; 11 folders (Box 10)
    - Maartens, Mark E., 1957-1958 (Box 10)
    - Maas, H.H., 1965-1970 (Box 10)
    - Maier, Harold G., 1964-1985; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Marcy, Carl, 1956-1966 (Box 10)
    - Margulies, Robert, 1959-1964 (Box 10)
    - Massel, Mark S., 1959-1973 (Box 10)
    - Mathews, Craig, 1964-1965 (Box 10)
    - Mathijsen, M. Pierre, 1961-1979 (Box 10)
    - Mayne, Richard, 1960-1976 (Box 10)
    - Mazzoni, Cosimo, 1987-1994 (Box 10)
    - Meeker, Leonard C., 1956-1972 (Box 10)
    - Meij, Arjen, 1974-1990; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Merillat, H.C.L. (American Society of International Law), 1956-1967; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Mestmäcker, Ernst-Joachim, 1963-1989; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Metzger, Stanley D., 1956-1971 (Box 11)
    - Michigan Journal of International Law, 1984-1991 (Box 11)
    - Michigan Law Review, 1964-1974 (Box 11)
    - Miller, Arthur S., 1962-1969 (Box 11)
    - Minunni, V., 1959-1960 (Box 11)
    - Mosler, Herman, 1957-1970 (Box 11)
    - Murden, Forrest D., 1958-1959 (Box 11)
    - N, 1957-1994; 4 folders (Box 11)
    - Nadelmann, Kurt H., 1960-1972 (Box 11)
    - Newburg, Andre W.G., 1964-1968 (Box 11)
    - Nicholson, Thomas, 1959-1972 (Box 11)
    - Norberg, Charles R., 1956-1977 (Box 11)
    - Norris, George, Jr., 1959 (Box 11)
    - Nurick, Lester (International Finance Corporation), 1956-1958 (Box 11)
    - Nussbaum, Michael, 1963-1967 (Box 11)
    - O, 1956-1994; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - O'Brien, John G. (Judge Advocate General's School), 1957-1960 (Box 11)
    - O'Donnell, Ashton J., 1956-1959 (Box 11)
    - Oliver, Covey T., 1956-1979; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Ouin, Marc, 1958-1960 (Box 11)
    - Oxford University Press, 1982-1995 (Box 11)
    - P, 1956-1995; 6 folders (Box 11)
    - Parry, Clive, 1959-1974 (Box 12)
    - Personal, 1962-1968 (Box 12)
    - Pescatore, Pierre, 1978-1980 (Box 12)
    - Pettiti, Louis Edmond, 1959-1962 (Box 12)
    - Phoenix Project, 1970-1972 (Box 12)
    - Pollak, Louis H., 1956-1978 (Box 12)
    - Popper, David H., 1957-1973 (Box 12)
    - Puente Egido, J., 1987-1989 (Box 12)
    - Q, 1984-1991 (Box 12)
    - Querner, D.P., 1971 (Box 12)
    - R, 1959-1995; 7 folders (Box 12)
    - Reese, Willis L.M. (Parker School of Foreign and Comparative Law, Columbia University), 1961-1965 (Box 12)
    - Reuter, Paul, 1958-1968 (Box 12)
    - Rey, M. Jean, 1959-1968 (Box 12)
    - Rheinstein, Max, 1958-1968 (Box 12)
    - Riese, Otto, 1961-1965 (Box 12)
    - Riesenfeld, Stefan A., 1958-1978 (Box 12)
    - Robertson, A.H., 1958-1973 (Box 12)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1976-1982 (Box 12)
    - Rupp, Hans, 1963-1981; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - S
      - 1956-1973, 6 folders (Box 12)
      - 1974-1994, 9 folders (Box 13)
    - Salmon, Jean, 1982-1984 (Box 13)
    - Samkalden, Ivo, 1961-1965 (Box 13)
    - Sandberger, Georg, 1968-1971 (Box 13)
    - Sasse, Christoph and Howard Yourow, 1976-1981 (Box 13)
    - Schacter, Oscar, 1956-1980 (Box 13)
    - Schaetzel, J. Robert, 1957-1979 (Box 13)
    - Schanzer, George O., 1957-1962 (Box 13)
    - Scheingold, Stuart A., 1960-1974 (Box 13)
    - Scheinman, Lawrence, 1959-1962 (Box 13)
    - Schermers, Henry G., 1968-1990; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Schindler, Dietrich, 1961-1967 (Box 13)
    - Schmidt, Folke, 1959-1971 (Box 13)
    - Schoenbaum, Thomas J. (Dean Rusk Center for International and Comparative Law), 1964-1989; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Scott, Andrew M., 1957-1958 (Box 13)
    - Scott, Michael, 1959-1968 (Box 13)
    - Scott, Richard (UNESCO), 1960-1962 (Box 13)
    - Seidl-Hohenveldrn, Ignaz, 1958-1972 (Box 13)
    - Selvig, Erling Chr, 1962-1973 (Box 13)
    - Sepulveda, Cesar, 1961-1976 (Box 13)
    - Sielucka, Catherine K., 1966-1970 (Box 13)
    - Singer, J. David, 1961-1969 (Box 13)
    - Sisco, Joseph J., 1957-1970 (Box 13)
    - Slater, Joseph E., 1956-1981; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Smit, Hans, 1966-1974 (Box 13)
    - Smith, Jeffrey, 1972-1987 (Box 13)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1964-1966 (Box 14)
    - Sohn, Louis B., 1956-1973 (Box 14)
    - Spaak, Fer, 1976-1981 (Box 14)
    - Spantigati, Federico, 1959-1960 (Box 14)
    - Stanford University, 1956-1961 (Box 14)
    - Stason, Blythe, Jr., 1967-1969 (Box 14)
    - Stason, E. Blythe, 1956-1963 (Box 14)
    - State Department Internship, 1979-1982 (Box 14)
    - Stoessinger, John G. (Brookings Institution), 1962 (Box 14)
    - Strauss, Edward (American Council for Jean Monnet Studies), 1985-1995 (Box 14)
    - Strauss, Edward and Henry Leir, 1992-1994 (Box 14)
    - Strauss, Walter, 1963-1968 (Box 14)
    - Swan, Charles V., 1957-1959 (Box 14)
    - Szasz, Paul C., 1966-1979; 2 folders (Box 14)